<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>et al. | Calvin Leung</title>
    <link>leungcalvin.github.io/author/et-al./</link>
      <atom:link href="leungcalvin.github.io/author/et-al./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>et al.</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/leungcalvin.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>et al.</title>
      <link>leungcalvin.github.io/author/et-al./</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Bell Test: Measurement Settings from Milky Way Stars</title>
      <link>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/handsteiner2017cosmic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:18:11 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/handsteiner2017cosmic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a Cosmic Bell test, the statistical significance of the final result&amp;ndash;a violation of Bell locality&amp;ndash;is extremely sensitive to sky glow and color filter bandwidth overlap within the astronomical random number generators. Skyglow and filter overlap introduce &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; photons into (what is supposed to be) a cosmic Bell test, in which all setting pairs are astronomical in origin. I developed a formalism to take these effects into account for this groundbreaking paper led by Johannes
Handsteiner at the IQOQI-Vienna.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Bell Test Using Random Measurement Settings from High-Redshift Quasars</title>
      <link>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/rauch2018cosmic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:17:45 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/rauch2018cosmic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Weak Equivalence Principle with Optical and Near-Infrared Crab Pulses</title>
      <link>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/leung2018testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:16:50 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/leung2018testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first foray into serious astrophysics happened by accident when I realized that testing data from our astronomical random number generator could be used to time the Crab pulsar. This is nothing new, but I realized we could also set the first limits for equivalence principle violation for photons between visible and near-infrared light. Did we expect a violation? Of course not! To high-energy physics, optical and near-infrared photons are basically the same. There&amp;rsquo;s great work on measuring the differences between radio photons and gamma ray photons, for which any deviations from equivalence would be magnified, but those kinds of measurements are subject to all kinds of pulsar timing systematics (e.g. different instruments, different clocks, plasma dispersion).
However, nobody had used optical single photon detectors to study the Crab in different bands simultaneously (work done by Naletto et al. on AQUEYE uses one broad passband), and the opportunity to perform a precise, systematic-free measurement was too good to resist. The lesson learned was that differences in the shape of the pulsar&amp;rsquo;s light curve dominate phase estimation at the part-per-thousand level that we were able to resolve&amp;ndash;and the phase delay measurement becomes strongly method-dependent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomical Random Numbers for Quantum Foundations Experiments</title>
      <link>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/leung2018astronomical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:16:02 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>leungcalvin.github.io/publication/leung2018astronomical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I led a publication to rigorously answer the fascinating question of &amp;ldquo;How truly random are bits from astronomical photons?&amp;rdquo;, and came up with a few unique quantum optics experiments utilizing astronomical randomness. Some foundational thought experiments&amp;ndash;including quantum and classical variants of the familiar double-slit experiment&amp;ndash;can be interpreted in novel ways when implemented using random astronomical setting choices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
